EMPEROR GODAIGO
Takauji Ashikaga, the attack on the
Kamakura shogunate was indeed laborious.
To celebrate your service,
I grant you a character from my real name.
EXALTED
From today, you shall write your name
using the kanji for "exalted."
HEREBY KNOWN AS
TAKAUJI ASHIKAGA
Thank you. I'm very honored.
CE 1333 (GENKŌ YEAR 3)
AUGUST 5TH KYOTO
Thanks to you, I won back the country.
If there is a position in
the new imperial court that you want,
do not hesitate to tell me now.
I am just a soldier.
I cannot be a scribe.
However, my retainers behind us
are much too pure of heart
and exceedingly wise and brave
for the likes of me.
I would be very happy if you gave
them work in the imperial court.
Wow.
I heard he was
the warrior that ruined Kamakura.
I wonder how demonic his face is.
He has such a kind smile.
I could just melt!
He's human after all.
The Emperor's wish was granted.
The time has come
for the Emperor and the nobles
to replace the shogunate's rule
over the country.
Good work today.
What is it, Moronao?
ASHIKAGA HOUSE STEWARD
MORONAO OF KO
It's nothing.
I've been serving you
since you were a child.
But your smile has recently
seemed less and less human.
Don't say such a stupid thing.
I'm counting on you.
We're going to ask everyone
to support the Emperor.
Sir.
THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
Lord Takauji,
thank you for recommending me
as governor of Shinano.
Of course. You deserve the reward.
You were first to betray the Hojo
and fought as my retainer.
However, your province, Shinano,
has Hojo's top retainer,
Mr. Suwa, going strong.
Hojo's survivors are
definitely taking refuge there.
I trust you will sniff them out.
Those ticks.
I can tell there are four males
and one female.
Count on me, Lord Takauji.
My arrows and my eyes are
the most excellent in this country.
I will find and kill any little bug.
SADAMUNE OGASAWARA
SLUGGISH
Are you serious?
I've never seen anyone not be able
to cut through a bundle of straw.
Even on the offense,
Lord Tokiyuki's muscles are always
getting ready to escape.
As a result,
he's always timid when he swings.
You have to train diligently
and put your back into it.
SQUEEZE SQUEEZE
That's the opposite of what we want.
If we train his muscles
to attack too much,
his running-away muscles will weaken.
His attack and evasion will become
mediocre, and he'll lose his strong suit.
What are running-away muscles?
My lord, you're a good shot.
My father enjoyed
watching archery competitions.
Wow, what splendid skill you have,
Lord Tokiyuki!
Thank you.
Bulls-eye!
It's a clean bulls-eye!
You've done it, Lord Tokiyuki!
I know I look weak,
but I trained in archery a lot.
It's decided then.
Let's maximize your archery skills.
A general who just runs away all the
time is going to weaken his army's morale.
We should make the best
of Lord Tokiyuki's special skill.
He should learn how to attack
while he runs.
I wonder where I could find an instructor
to teach such an unorthodox method?
Lord Yorishige!
Sadamune Ogasawara of West Shinano
has stopped by for a surprise visit.
Sadamune?
Who's that?
Is he not an acquaintance from Kamakura?
I don't know him.
Perhaps he was not of a status
where he could freely come and go
to my father's residence?
Okay then.
For good measure,
hide and watch from that small shack.
Oh, Yorishige, it's been too long!
Thank you for coming all this way.
What brings you here, Sadamune?
Sorry for coming so suddenly.
I just wanted to greet you.
As you know, the shogunate has fallen.
The government has
returned to the Emperor Godaigo.
I have an Imperial Command from him.
He's appointed me, Sadamune Ogasawara,
as governor of Shinano.
IMPERIAL COMMAND = DECREE
*DO NOT DEFY
That is to say,
you take orders from me now.
Squish.
SUWA FAMILY MEMBER
MORITAKA SUWA
You were working for Suwa
just the other day.
Now you want to give us orders?
When the Kamakura shogunate fell,
I did a great service to the Emperor
by fighting the rebel Hojo.
But you… You took Hojo's side.
Many of you fought on their behalf,
so you can hardly complain when
your territory gets taken away from you.
Well, we will visit this issue
another time.
I came today for one more reason.
If you have any of the Hojo clan or any of
their important retainers sheltered here,
hand them over.
There's no way I'd be hiding someone.
How can I hand over
someone I haven't even seen?
Oh, you haven't even seen a Hojo?
In the distance, I can see two soldiers
behind the cedar tree
who are watching intently.
There's a man who clutches
his small knife, ready for strife.
There are children hidden and watching
from a small shack through slits.
They all look like people
suspiciously taking shelter to me!
You can't fool my all-seeing gaze,
Yorishige.
I'll catch all of them in no time.
That's all. I just wanted to say hello.
Take care.
Oh, and I forgot to mention.
I came in a hurry
and didn't bring any gifts.
Please accept a deer for Suwa Myojin.
Deer?
I hear it's good fortune if you catch
a deer with a split ear
at Suwa Grand Shrine.
-Sakae!
A fortuitous gift for you!
There's one split-eared doe!
That creep.
How is Miss Sakae?
She said it'll sew back together.
She laughed
and said it wasn't a big deal, but…
Sadamune Ogasawara is an expert archer
known throughout the country.
His vision and excellent
observational skills give him his edge.
We got a real troublesome one
as the governor of Shinano.
Damn it. That bug-eyed creep.
To think he'd aim at a simple
shrine maiden. I can't believe it.
What do you think, my lord?
He acts disgracefully as a warrior.
It's obvious he's a bug-eyed psychopath.
-But…
-But?
His archery was beautiful.
What an honest and generous boy.
-Even if it's his enemy…
-Of course what he did was not okay.
-…he appreciates skill.
-I don't condone his behavior.
Once he becomes a general,
this fair character will surely be useful.
And I just found a perfect instructor.
It's decided, Lord Tokiyuki.
The next game of tag is hide-and-seek.
Hide-and-seek?
Sadamune has two goals.
First, to find
any surviving Hojo family members.
And he'll use that as an excuse to,
two, weaken the amount of influence
the Suwa clan has.
You also have two goals.
First, never let them know who you are.
Second, absorb his archery technique.
OGASAWARA TERRITORY
SUWA TERRITORY
Sadamune will abuse
his position as governor,
and come to pick fights from now on.
GOVERNOR COMMAND
This means you'll get to see
his archery in action many times.
At times, you'll physically hide yourself.
Other times, you'll hide your identity.
Without being too close or too far,
you'll observe his form.
It's hide-and-seek
from his eyes and arrows!
The thrill is not knowing
whether you'll be identified or shot!
Aren't you excited, Lord Tokiyuki?
I heard a rumor, Mr. Sadamune.
I hear that in three days…
ASSISTANT TO GOVERNOR OF SHINANO
SUKEFUSA ICHIKAWA
…we'll get to enjoy a dog-shooting
competition at Suwa Grand Shrine.
So with that being said,
I have an excellent plan.
We shall weaken Yorishige Suwa's influence
and search out the Hojo survivors.
I'm going to participate in
the dog-shooting competition.
I'll start a fight and set conditions.
When I win the competition,
I can get what I want.
GRIN
That's a splendid idea.
That felt so gross to have him
whisper to me with those protruding eyes!
DAY OF DOG-SHOOTING COMPETITION
Damn it. I can't hit anything!
I have to get better.
Lord Tokiyuki, you're next.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Shizuku, it's dangerous to say
Lord Tokiyuki's name in this crowd.
From now on, use a false name.
Think of a pseudonym.
Then I'll call you Big Brother.
What?
My lord!
You have to see this!
We have a surprise contestant!
The governor of Shinano,
Sadamune Ogasawara,
is jumping into the competition!
Why is he acting like he can just join in?
And so persistently…
Dog-shooting competitions
are Shinano's main event.
As the governor of Shinano,
I had to liven up the party.
Am I allowed, Yorishige?
Of course. I welcome you.
You have five arrows.
Scoring is based on the location
of the shot and shooting posture as usual.
Release the dogs!
Right-handed shot on the dog's stomach.
Four points!
Right-handed shot on the dog's head.
Five points!
Right-handed shot on the dog's neck.
What skill.
He's shooting all right-handed shots
that score high points.
LEFT SIDED
With the right-handed shot,
it's hard to pull the bow
when you must twist your body.
RIGHT SIDED
And what's more,
he's hitting the dogs all on their
critical points, on their upper half.
Mr. Yorishige is quivering?
Is he terrified of Sadamune's skills?
SHAKE SHAKE SHAKE
It's not that. In the future,
they consider this animal abuse.
But during this time,
this is a normal thing.
If this is a problem, I'm in trouble.
Who in the world are you justifying to?
Now let's see, what place am I now?
Individually, you're in first.
Oh?
Are you shocked that
a surprise contestant has first place?
So is this the level
of Suwa Grand Shrine to the God of War?
Don't get cocky!
There are still
many strong competitors waiting!
Then let those strong competitors
come bet on a one-on-one match.
A bet?
As you know,
I'm looking for Hojo survivors.
If none of you can win against me,
you'll allow me to search
your suspicious folks' homes for them
without complaint.
That scumbag,
saying whatever conditions he wants.
He only has a few men, but he's so bold.
We can't oppose him too carelessly
since he was appointed by the Emperor.
On the other hand,
if he comes out and says what he wants,
he won't get off scot-free.
This is how Sadamune and I advance
and retreat in our fight without a fight.
I'm in on that bet.
If we win, then with your authority,
you won't let our territory be searched.
How's that?
You bit the bait.
As a Suwa landlord, you have your pride.
If you're challenged
in front of your people, you must accept.
Lose the bet and suffer embarrassment!
Afterwards, if we can find the Hojo
refugees, we'll expose your crimes!
Suwa will fall, and you will
have to surrender to Ogasawara.
HOJO
And what strong competitor will you offer?
Strong competitor?
For you, I think this child is sufficient.
Pop!
His name is Chojumaru.
He's Suwa's least competent,
so I think it'll be a good match.
Are you mocking me, Yorishige?
It's not interesting
if we do things the normal way.
So let's make a rule that you can also win
points by shooting at each other's bodies.
Huh? Are you shaking in your boots?
Unlike the shrine maiden you shot
the other day, this boy's got a weapon!
Stop this, Lord Yorishige!
The young lord's combat prowess
is that of a rabbit. Suwa will end!
He's someone whose face goes "sigh"
and loses.
Don't underestimate his weakness!
What they said!
I don't understand why you're purposely
making the chased battle
against the chaser.
There's great worth in it.
Battling against a master
will let you grow greatly.
Lord Tokiyuki, I can see
a bright future full of growth for you
if you go against him.
I will say this clearly.
After the battle,
you will learn a cool new skill.
At least, that's a feeling I get.
I wonder if it'll happen?
Speak clearly!
Now, what shall we do today?
As general of Hojo, you can
choose danger and grow, or run away.
It's up to you.
That's an unfair way to put it.
You're always making me do what you want.
If I've decided to kill Takauji, then…
Give me the arrows, Shizuku.
What a strange person.
He's always running away,
but he doesn't run away
from the most formidable enemy here.
I see his future clearly now too.
He won't run away from the
important things he's set his heart on.
Kid, I'll make you pay
the price for disrespecting me.
Please send the bill to Mr. Yorishige.
I can tell you're unskilled
by just looking at you.
You really think you can win, kid?
Only God knows.
Begin!
Right, should I gain points
by hitting dogs per usual?
Of course not! The kid is my target!
Damn kid!
You really wish to anger me?
It doesn't have to land.
Make him completely focus on you
as the target with your first blow.
A warrior is a creature that
can't turn down a challenge.
He will, without a doubt, shoot back.
First, dodge his shots.
Sadamune doesn't like to
shoot in rapid succession
because he gives his all for every shot.
You'll have time
till he shoots the next arrow.
Till then,
shoot a dog and gain some points.
There should be a red dog that runs
close by so as to be an easy target.
That dog was trained
for entertainment purposes!
There's such a thing?
Make sure you aim, you lousy shooter!
I only get my venison reward
if you hit me.
One more shot!
That's it.
Left-handed shot on the torso. One point!
The brat got the first point!
Damn kid!
Afterwards, simply focus on evading.
For someone that doesn't know you,
it'll be difficult to hit you.
TOP MAJOR LEAGUER'S BEST SPEED
ABOUT 160 KM/H
THIRD KEISEI SKYLINER TOP SPEED
QUICKEST 36 MIN.
ARROWS WERE SLOWER
THAN MODERN ARROWS.
DODGING THEM WAS NOT UNHEARD OF.
Dang. This is my last arrow.
I still don't have any points.
If I miss, that seals my loss.
Sadamune is feeling the pressure now.
Will he readjust his aim toward the dogs?
The dogs chosen for this event are
Suwa Grand Shrine's best runners.
Not even Sadamune can hit you so easily.
Using your skilled evasion
to your advantage,
aim for Sadamune
with your remaining arrows.
Once he fears being your target,
he'll become frustrated and confused.
Having lost all composure,
he won't even be able to aim at the dogs.
This is bad.
Sadamune is in Lord Tokiyuki's blind spot.
It's impossible for the lord to aim
no matter how he twists or turns.
To win a war,
simply having a bow and arrow won't do.
You must be on horseback in order to
gain an indispensable vantage point.
This isn't
a dog-shooting competition anymore.
It's an equestrian archery showdown
you'd see on the battlefield.
Lord Moritaka.
Suwa Grand Shrine's king of commentary.
Chojumaru continuously attempts to
throw Sadamune out of his blind spot
by frantically turning his horse.
Without even holding on to the reins,
Sadamune trails him easily.
Even Emperor Godaigo praised
Sadamune Ogasawara's martial arts.
It's good.
The Emperor said "It's good!"
KING
"Sadamune should be
an example for all warriors."
Thus, Ogasawara was granted special
permission from the Emperor himself
to use the character "king"
in his family crest.
Sadamune's discipline of martial arts
is still widely practiced to this day,
in the 21st century.
With your focus so divided
between steering your horse and dodging,
don't think that split second where
you forget to evade will escape my gaze!
NANBOKUCHO GAME OF TAG
ALL-SEEING DEMON OGASAWARA
Right-handed shot on the opponent's head.
Five points!
Whoa, what a comeback!
That Sadamune didn't hold back!
He's winning by four points!
Now, I've exhausted all my arrows.
You're free to aim for whatever you like.
Dog or human.
I won't give up my position
in your blind spot though.
I'll run my horse into you to
hinder your shot when you aim for a dog.
The game is over, kid.
There's blood. It hurts.
There's no winning. I'm scared!
If this was a real arrow, I'd be dead.
Why do you run?
Are you afraid?
Are you uselessly struggling?
This is fun!
Translated by Emily Walton
EPISODE 5 (YEAR OF 1333): SETTLING THE SCORE!
A DOG-SHOOTING COMPETITION AND THEN...
Let's go!